■
本字幕由 YYeTs人人影视 原创翻译制作
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新 请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
■
翻译：屁屁  猫中之王  芒果妖怪  midichlorian  板栗桑  yvonnez  爱卿遛小鸟  米苏
时间轴：子衿   三水
■
校对：大卫熊  草草     后期&监制：瓜瓜
你真美  妮基・希特
You are very beautiful, Nikki Heat.
只可惜我现在得杀了你
It is too bad that I have to kill you now.
比你更丑的男人都试过  德拉格
Uglier men than you have tried, Drago.
你扇我巴掌
You have slapped me.
我不会
I will not have--
玩洋娃娃呢
Playing with dolls, are we?
这些是人形公仔
These are action figures.
我借他们来创作场景
I am using them to envision a scene.
我还欠编辑几章《冰冻之心》
I owe a few chapters of "Frozen Heat" to my editor,
但我一页都写不出
and I've not been able to write a page.
也许和贝克特办件案子
Maybe a case with Beckett might,
就能激发灵感呢
you know, spark something.
她在准备庭审
She's prepping for a trial.
是信件吗
That the mail?
对  谢天谢地阿丽克西斯
Oh, yeah, yeah. Thank God Alexis is
终于收到一些大学的回信了
finally getting some college acceptance letters.
她的朋友们几周前就陆陆续续收到了
Her friends started getting them weeks ago.
理查德・卡塞尔
Richard Castle,
你到底在玩什么把戏
what on earth are you playing at?
我不想让阿丽克西斯再经历
I don't want Alexis to have to live through
收到斯坦福大学拒信的噩梦了
that Stanford rejection nightmare again.
所以我要藏着这些信
So I'm holding the letters.
这样一来  她一下子收齐这些信
This way, she gets them all at once,
有坏消息的同时也有好消息
and she'll get all the good news with the bad.
理查德  这是你有史以来最蠢的主意了
Richard, that is the dumbest idea you've ever had.
你得在她神经崩溃前
Now you've got to give her these letters
把这些信给她
before she has a nervous breakdown.
好啦  我会的
Okay, I will. I will.
不过你得承认
Though you have to admit,
看她神经崩溃挺有趣的
watching her have a nervous breakdown is pretty funny.
我才不这么认为呢
Unlike yours.
你的写作怎么办
Now what are we gonna do about your writing?
不知道  我就是需要些  不同以往的东西
Oh, I don't know. I just need something... different,
新东西
something new,
比如说
something like...
头条新闻
发现人头
人头
severed heads.
Severed heads?
死者是在午夜之后被人枪杀的
The victim was found shot to death after midnight.
据警方称  他的包里装了三个人头
According to police, his bag contained three severed heads.
斯勒特警探  你能说说
Detective Slaughter, what can you tell us about--
趁我没开枪打爆你的摄像机  给我拿开
Get that camera out of my face before I put a bullet in it!
妈
Oh-ho, Mother,
忘了人头吧
forget severed heads.
我想去认识这个人
I want to meet that guy.
亲爱的  你已经有缪斯了
You already have a Muse, darling.
没错  缪斯是用来激发灵感的
Yes, well, Muses are to provide inspiration,
但现在我完全没有受到激发
and right now I ain't getting any.
妮基・希特警探
So Detective Nikki Heat,
来认识一下斯勒特警探吧
meet Detective Slaughter.
把这东西放在会议室
You know what? Park that in the conference room.
谢谢
Thank you.
卡塞尔  你来干嘛啊
Hey. Castle, what are you doing here?
就是几天没见你了
I just haven't seen you in a few days.
我觉得应该过来看看你怎么样了
Thought I'd drop by, see how you're doing.
谢谢  真贴心
Thank you. That's so sweet.
事实上我很好
Um, I'm great, actually.
庭审准备得很好
The trial prep is going really well.
我能准时下班回家
I've been getting home at a decent hour, and...
见到你很高兴
It's great to see you.
我也是
It's good to see you, too.
关于那个叫斯勒特的黑帮组警探
Hey, listen, do you know anything about
你都知道些什么
this gang cop named Slaughter?
人头凶案  你就是为此来的
The severed-heads homicide, that's why you're here?
不是
Uh, no. I mean,
只不过既然你忙着准备庭审
just, since you're busy prepping for the trial,
我就是想查查这个斯勒特的底
I just thought I'd look into this Slaughter guy,
大致了解一下这人  做为背景调查
get a sense of who he is for the background research,
就是  那个
the-- the...
除非你对此有问题
Unless that's a problem.
不  没问题
No, not a problem.
太好了  那我能在哪找到他呢
Great. So where would I find him?
尸体在哪就去哪呗
Wherever the body is.
亲爱的  你还是承认吧
Darlin', you might as well confess.
我知道是你杀了他
I know you killed him
以便你我共度美好时光
so we could spend some quality time together.
即使你是地球上最后一个男人我也不会勾搭你
Not if you were the last man on earth.
别以为我会知难而退
Don't think I'm not up to the challenge.
不如跳过你的大男子幻想
How about we skip the macho fantasy,
我直接告诉你死因吧
and I just tell you cause of death?
让我猜猜  中弹而亡
Let me guess-- lead poisoning?
胸口三枪
Three shots to the chest.
最有可能是短时间内大量失血而死
Most likely died of blood loss within minutes.
我就知道格林奇终会躺在这儿
Always figured Glitch would end up on this table.
格林奇是他的绰号  因为他做事一团糟
Glitch-- it's his street name on account, he's such a screwup.
你帮我把子弹拿出来了吗
You fish the slugs out for me?
看见没  你果然爱我
Ah. See? You do love me.
我猜是点32的吧
.32s, I'm guessing.
-你在说子弹对吧  -没错
- You're talking about the bullets, right? - Yeah.
你不问人头的事了吗
Aren't you gonna ask about the heads?
-你是谁  -这位是卡塞尔
- Who the hell are you? - That's Castle.
他是作家  12分局的顾问
He's a writer, and he consults with the 12th.
好奇怪  这些头都不新鲜
It's weird. You can tell they aren't fresh.
能闻出来  甲醛  还带有些许腐臭
You can smell it-- formaldehyde with a soupcon of decay.
从头发里的泥土看来
Judging from the dirt in the hair,
应该是死者挖出了尸体
I'd say our victim dug the bodies up
然后砍下了他们的头
and then cut the heads off.
真厉害啊  夏洛克
No kidding, Sherlock.
我早派人去查看本地墓园了
I already got UNIS checking out the local cemeteries,
不过那也与你无关
not that it's any of your business.
里克・卡塞尔  正如劳拉所说
Rick Castle, and like Laura said,
我和12分局的贝克特探长合作
I work out of the 1-2 with Detective Beckett.
是这样的
Here's the thing--
我希望能跟着你办这件案子
I was hoping I could ride along with you on this one,
就一两天
just for a day or two.
-不行  -不行
- No. - No?
我不需要有个作家在边上闲晃
I need a writer hanging around
就像我不需要梅毒一样
like I need a case of the crabs.
真是
That's...
我要如何让你改变心意
What could I say to change your mind?
这件外套不错
Well, that is a very fine coat.
你穿上会很好看
And it would look fabulous on you.
成交了吗
So are we good?
不
No.
再见了  美人
See ya, gorgeous.
你说我给你外套的话就能跟着你的
You said I could ride along if I gave you my coat.
我可没说过
I never said that.
你暗示了
It was implied.
我一个人办案
Look, I work alone.
你说什么都不会改变这一点的
Nothing you say is gonna change that.
我是市长的朋友
I'm friends with the mayor.
什么
Yeah?
既然我这算是求你帮忙
And seeing as how I'm asking you for a favor here,
那我就欠你一个人情
that would mean I would owe you one in return.
市长的朋友就是我的朋友
Well, any friend of the mayor is a friend of mine.
我们第一步做什么
What's our first move?
告诉格林奇爸爸他儿子的死讯
Break the news to Glitch's dad.
真给力  贝克特绝不会把车开上人行道
That was awesome. Beckett never drives on the sidewalk.
你要是想跟我混
If you're gonna hang with me,
就得知道些基本规矩
we're gonna lay out some ground rules.
第一条规矩
Rule number one,
不准说"给力"
do not use the word "Awesome."
你是个成年人了
You're a grown man.
第二条规矩  别给我惹麻烦
Rule number two, stay outta my way.
就这些
Is that it?
差不多都概括了
That's kinda all-encompassing.
做这工作最艰难的就是
This is the hardest part of the job--
通知家人死讯
breaking the news to the family.
你是什么风格  寥寥数语却深表同情
So what's your style, terse yet compassionate,
-用词小心但底气十足  -布莱恩
- sensitive but strong? - Brian.
格林奇正躺在停尸房
Glitch is in the morgue.
有人给他吃了三颗子弹
Someone pumped three rounds into him.
节哀顺变
We're sorry for your loss.
什么  节哀
My what? My "Loss"?
你他妈是谁  跟我说节哀
Who the hell are you to talk about my loss?
你那小子卷进了个不同一般的大麻烦
Your boy was into something bad, worse than usual.
你知道是什么情况吗
What do you know about it?
就算知道也没必要告诉你
And why would I tell ya even if I knew?
有尸体被砍下了头
Well, it involved cutting the heads off of dead guys.
你小子不像是会做这种傻事的人
Doesn't sound like your boy's brand of stupid.
我的儿子
My son...
是身处乱世的单纯少年
was a simple lad operating in difficult times.
瞧不起他  你后果自负
You disparage his memory at your peril.
现在
Now...
我得去通知他的妈妈  安排后事
I've gotta go tell his mom, make arrangements.
这人不好对付
That's a hard man.
心慈手软可做不了西部帮派的头号人物
You don't get to be top leg breaker in the Westies by being soft.
难怪他没透露点风声
No wonder he didn't give us anything useful.
我也没抱希望
Never thought he would.
他是那种喜欢"私设公堂"的人
He's a "Take the law into your own hands" Kinda guy.
你是说他会自己解决杀死格林奇的人
You think he's gonna hunt down Glitch's killer himself.
没错  我们得跟着他
Yeah, and we're gonna follow him.
关键在于赶在他杀人之前出面调停
The tricky part's gonna be interceding before he kills the guy.
走  他已经上路了
Let's go. He's on the move.
你觉得他会去哪
where do you think he's going?
要知道就不用跟着他了
I don't know. That's why we're following him.
喂
Yeah?
好样的
Outstanding.
警员发现了格林奇拿到人头的那个公墓
Unis found the cemetery where Glitch got the heads.
距离犯罪现场四个街区
Four blocks from the crime scene.
多谢了  老兄
Thanks, brother.
等回到办公室去查到这些人
Back to the office, run these names down,
看是谁的脑袋
find out who these heads belong to.
不用等  我的团队现在就能查
Why wait when I can have my team run them right now?
你有团队
you got a team?
-你好  -我给你发了三个名字
- Hello? - I am texting you three names,
都是刚死不久的人
all recently deceased.
需要你帮我查查
I need you to run 'em for me.
贝克特现在手头没有案子
Beckett's not working a case right now.
不  我和黑帮组的斯勒特办案呢
No, I'm running and gunning with Slaughter from gangs.
那就叫他自己查
Then have him run the names.
我不是你手下的人
I don't work for you.
埃斯波西托
Ah, Esposito,
你太幽默了
You are too funny.
他在你旁边  是吧
He's there, isn't he?
好吧
All right.
你想让我帮你撑门面  就要付出代价
If you want me to make you look good, it's gonna cost.
尼克斯队的前排座位
Front-row knicks tickets.
很好
Sounds good.
再顺便说一句
Oh, and, uh, by the way,
你的搭档斯勒特
your boy Slaughter--
在黑帮组可是大名鼎鼎
he's got quite a reputation in gangs.
外号是"天煞孤星"
His nickname is "The widowmaker."
他的前三个搭档都死了
His last three partners were all killed
因公殉职
in the line of duty.
-还好吗  -嗯
- All good? - Yeah.
你觉得他们之中有人是杀手
You think one of those guys could be the killer?
不  他只是在打探消息
Nah, he's just trolling for info,
我们只要
which means we watch
等着瞧
and wait.
不用了  谢谢
Ahh. Ah, no, thanks.
好吧
Okay, sure.
那么
So...
他们管你叫天煞孤星
they call you the widowmaker.
他们总把傻瓜塞给我  这又不是我的错
Hey, not my fault they keep sticking me with idiots.
说到搭档
Speaking of partners,
我看过你的搭档  她可是热辣滚烫
I've seen pictures of yours. She's smokin' hot.
和她有一腿吗
You're tappin' that, right?
什么  没有
What? No.
没有  你有什么毛病
No? What's wrong with you?
没...没什么毛病
Nothing's--nothing's wrong with me.
我们只是朋友
We're just friends.
男人想要朋友  买条狗就行了
Man needs a friend, he gets a dog.
那样的女人  不能翻云覆雨
Woman like that, you storm the beaches
也得死缠烂打  拜托
or die trying. Come on.
他往那家酒吧走了  该上场了
He's heading for that bar. Showtime.
带了枪吗
You packin'?
带枪  我不是警察
Packing? No, I'm not a cop.
我的防弹衣上写着"作家"呢
My vest says "Writer" On it.
第三条规矩  跟我办事就得全副武装
Rule number three, you ride with me, you ride strapped.
走吧
Come on.
那不是触犯了相关法规
hey, hey, what about regulations?
你不是签了弃权证书吗
You signed a waiver, didn't you?
你走前门  我走后门
Okay, you take the front, I'll go in the back.
等等  等等  我们该叫上后援吧
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa. Shouldn't we call for backup?
你还有写着"作家"的裙子吗
You got a skirt that says "Writer" on it, too?
没有
No.
给我十秒钟  然后就闯进去
Come on. Give me ten seconds, then go in hard.
大喊纽约警局  越大声越好
Yell out "NYPD," The louder, the better.
纽约警局
N-Y-P-D!
我是相关平民调查员  都不准动
Associated civilian investigator. Nobody move.
-把枪放下  人渣  -你叫我什么
- Drop the gun, dirtbag! - What did you call me?
人...人渣
D-dirtbag.
放下枪  不然你老婆就能在
Drop it or your wife will be getting
殡仪馆买一赠一了
a volume discount at the mortuary.
过来  坐下
Come on. Set down
抓住他  夏洛克
Get him, Sherlock!
抓住了
I got him!
要跑了  要跑了
I don't--I don't got him. I don't got him.
I don't got him. I don't got him.
帮个忙
Little help!
你干的很好
You're doing fine.
好样的  夏洛克  好小子
Well done, Sherlock. Attaboy.
第四季 第二十一集
探
妙
书
灵
探
妙
书
灵
我怎么听说卡塞尔
What's this I hear about Castle
和别的警察一起去查案了
researching with another cop?
你没有文件要填吗
Don't you have some files to fill out?
我相信这只是阶段性而已  你也知道卡塞尔
I'm sure it's just a phase. You know Castle.
他可能是被断头案
He's probably caught up in the severed heads
和帮派啥的迷住了
and the rush of The Gangster Squad--
我才不关心他
I don't care what...
他
what...
卷入了什么事  只要他
he's wrapped up in just so long as he...
别来
stays out of my...
烦我  谢了
hair. Thanks.
暂时帮我看管一下
Hey, put him on ice for me, huh?
希亚  肥水不留外人田  知道吗
Shea, keep it in the family, huh?
-审讯室在哪儿  -就在那里  第一扇门
- Where's interrogation? - Right there. First door right there.
你给我过来
Come on, you.
这是怎么回事
What the hell happened?
你真该看到那一幕
Oh, you should have seen it.
斯勒特先发制人  擒住了一个
Slaughter got the drop on the one guy,
可另一个想逃走
but the other guy tried to make a break for it.
我只得把他放倒
I had to take his ass down.
你干了什么  你开玩笑吧
You what? Are you kidding me?
你是个作家  卡塞尔  不是个警察
You're a writer, Castle. Not a cop.
我可以照顾好自己  是你从不给我机会
Hey, I can take care of myself. You just never give me a chance.
当然  因为我不想让你挂掉
Yeah, because I'm not trying to get you killed.
他要用我们的审讯室干什么
And what is he doing using our box?
是我请他来的
Well, I invited him to.
卡塞尔  你没这个资格
Castle, that's not your place.
我想你不会介意的  再说  斯勒特这种人
I didn't think you'd mind. Besides, guys like Slaughter,
他们总是从这个分局跳到那个分局
they just float from precinct to precinct, you know?
就像游牧者
They're like nomads,
在纽约市街头游荡
wandering the streets of New York City,
除暴安良  杀人无赦
kicking ass and taking names,
虽然这句话的本意不是如此
which isn't the most original turn of phrase,
但他真是了不起的人物
but the character is so great.
绝对能为下一本妮基・希特系列带来冲击
It's really gonna help me shake up this next Nikki Heat book.
没问题  只要你能活着把书写下来
Yeah, sure, if you live long enough to actually write about it.
格林奇不是我杀的
I didn't kill Glitch.
那他父亲为什么去找你麻烦
Then why'd his father come after you?
我不知道  可你得说服他我是清白的
I don't know, but you gotta convince him that I'm innocent.
不  不是的
No, no, no, no.
是你得说服我
You gotta convince me
否则我就把你丢进拘留室
or I'm gonna park you in holding
坐山观虎斗
then sit back and marvel
布莱恩如何赤手空拳地
at how Brian removes your limbs
把你四肢拧下来
with his bare hands.
我昨晚在长岛我姐姐家
I was at my sister's house on Long Island last night.
你可以打电话去问她
You can call and ask her.
那为什么布莱恩认为是你杀了他儿子
So why does Brian think you killed his son?
非要这样吗  希亚
Really, Shea?
[美国警探剧]
要我再次上演"帅虎猛龙"的戏码吗
Want me to bust out Jake and the Fatman again?
布莱恩听说我和格林奇起过争执
Brian heard me and Glitch had a falling out,
可我们并没有
but we didn't.
那只是
It's just...
芬恩・洛克让我们都离他远点
Finn Rourke told us all to stay away from him.
西部帮派的老大让你们排挤格林奇吗
The head of the Westies made you freeze Glitch out?
为什么
Why?
他上周又办砸了一项差事
He screwed up another job last week.
他因为汽油用光  就把一辆满载偷来的
He abandoned a truck full of stolen medical equipment
医疗器材的卡车丢在罗斯福路上了
on the F.D.R. after he ran out of gas.
芬恩不杀格林奇的唯一理由就是布莱恩了
The only reason finn didn't have Glitch killed was Brian,
因为他知道如果他儿子出了事
because he knew he was crazy enough
布莱恩是会疯狂到敢去追杀他
to go after him if anything happened to his kid.
为什么格林奇会有一袋子人头
Why did Glitch have a bag full of heads?
不知道
No clue.
你最后一次见到他是什么时候
When's the last time you saw him?
两天以前
Two days ago.
他说他要去干点什么
He said he was gonna do something
跟西部帮派和好
to get back in good with the Westies.
他有说是什么事吗
Did he say what it was?
没  我也没问
No, and I didn't ask.
格林奇怎么会觉得砍下死人的头
How could Glitch think that cutting the heads off dead bodies
可以让他跟西部帮派和好呢
would get him back in good with the Westies?
他不是什么有头脑的人
He wasn't a deep thinker.
我可不会费尽心思去找他的动机
I wouldn't knock myself out looking for motive.
卡布奇诺
Cappuccino?
第四条规矩
Rule four.
卡塞尔
Castle.
太好了
Perfect.
谢谢  非常感谢
Thank you. Thank you very much.
埃斯波西托说
Esposito said
你有东西要给他
you'd have something for him.
那个
Uh, that's...
告诉他东西就到
Tell him--tell him they're on their way.
谢了
Thank you.
好了
All right.
看来那些人头的身份查到了
Looks like we got I.D.s on our heads.
三个人都是沟城帮的成员
All three belong to members of the Trench Town Posse.
我靠  谜题解开了
Hot damn. Mystery solved.
沟城帮
Trench Town Posse,
牙买加帮派  掌管着布鲁克林到
Jamaican gang-- runs girls and drugs
布朗克斯的卖淫和毒品交易
from Brooklyn to the Bronx.
他们正和西部帮派为争夺
They're fighting a turf war with the Westies
莫萨高地的地盘而战
over the Morningside Heights.
我猜格林奇是想用砍下西部帮派敌方的头
I bet Glitch thought he could make his bones
作为弥补过失的筹码
by cutting the heads off of Westie enemies.
我打赌他打算把这些头
Bet he planned on putting those heads
放在某些牙买加高层人士的床上
in some high-ranking Jamaican beds.
就像电影《教父》里的马头一样
Like a horse's head, "The Godfather."
这是你说过的最蠢的话了
Yeah, that's the stupidest thing you said yet,
蠢到连格林奇都会觉得是个好主意
and just dumb enough to seem smart to Glitch.
根据对他的了解  他肯定走漏了消息
And knowing that boy, he'd run his mouth,
牙买加人知道了这事  伏击了他
Jamaicans hear about it, and they ambush him.
快走
Come on.
我认识和牙买加人有关系的线人
I got a source on the street tied in with the Jamaicans.
他应该可以告诉我们情报
He'll be able to give us intel.
我爱死这种快攻办案方式了
I love this run-and-gun police work.
你在生气
You're upset.
没有
No.
好吧  我是生气  行了吧
Yes. Okay? Fine. Yes.
我以为
I thought that
我俩之间变得更加亲密了
the two of us were actually getting closer together,
现在看起来他是在疏远我
and now it seems like he's just pulling away.
你问过他原因吗
Have you asked him why?
问过  他说
Yes, and he said...
"一切都很好"
"Oh, everything is fine."
你为什么觉得不好呢
What makes you think it isn't?
因为他的所作所为都太混账了
Because he's acting like a complete jackass!
他手挽着小妞出现在分局
He shows up at the precinct with these bimbos hanging on his arm,
现在他又围在其他警察身边
And now he's running around with another cop.
那个其他警察是女性吗
Is this other cop a woman?
不  不  为什么...
No! No. Why...
为什么这么问
Why would you even ask that?
这根本不是重点
That's not even the point.
重点是  我不明白为什么他要这么做
The point is, I don't understand why he's acting like this.
我是说  我做了什么呢
I mean, what did I do?
也许  从他的视角来看
Well, maybe, from his point of view,
问题在于  你没做什么
The question is, what didn't you do?
等等  什么
Wait. What?
什么意思
W-what do you mean?
你中枪的时候  卡塞尔说他爱你
When you were shot, Castle said that he loved you.
那是多久前的事
How long ago was that?
七个月前
Seven months ago,
可我那时没准备好听他说那句话
but I wasn't ready to hear that then--
你觉得他用行动在告诉你什么
What do you think he's telling you with his behavior?
也许是
That maybe
他已经不再等候了
he's not there anymore?
也许他还没准备好
That maybe he's not ready?
要是我等太久了呢
What if I waited too long?
你不是在等  凯特  而是休养
You weren't waiting, Kate. You were healing.
是的  可也许在这段时间
Yeah, but then in the meantime,
他向前看了
he's moved on.
或者他在保护自己
Or he's protecting himself
不愿承担更多的感情风险
by not taking more emotional risks.
那我该怎么办
So then what do I do?
你想怎么办
What do you want to do?
要我就这么办
I tell you what I'd do,
我会对你的搭档暴露出原始野性
I'd go all caveman on that partner of yours.
让她看看什么才是真男人的作风
Show her what time it is in real-man land.
真男人的作风
Real-man land?
刚刚在停尸间
Oh, is that what you were showing Laura
你展现给劳拉的那种吗
when we were back at the morgue?
只是给她点关注
Just throw a little attention her way,
逗她开心
make her happy.
我现在想要的是那个新来的红发妞
You know who I'm mackin' on is this hot new redhead
她才刚来那边工作
just started working there.
那妞才十几岁的样子
That girl's barely street legal.
红头发吗
A redhead?
是啊
Yeah.
五尺五寸高  蓝眼睛  实习生
About 5'5", blue eyes, intern?
是啊  你认识她吗
Yeah. You know her?
那是我女儿
That's my daughter.
真的吗  那妞的屁股
Seriously? That girl got an ass--
放松点  夏洛克  逗你呢
Relax, Sherlock. I'm just playin'.
好吧
All right.
不管怎样  你都不许你碰我女儿
As long as we're clear that my daughter's off-limits.
就一个作家而言你挥拳还挺狠
Yeah. You pack a little punch there for a writer.
那是我要找的人
There's my guy.
别  你待在这儿
Nah, you stay here.
注意下周围情况
Keep an eye out.
-你没事吧  -问到了个名字
- You okay? - I got a name.
里面发生什么事了  你杀了他吗
What happened in there? Did you kill him?
你不会想知道的  我们没来过这儿
You don't want to know. We were never here.
-你在干什么  -妈呀
- What are you doing? - Jeez!
你没事吧
You okay?
那家伙疯了
That guy is insane.
是啊  我知道  我早说了
Yeah, I know. I tried to tell you.
不  他是个疯子
No, he's insane.
为什么  他干什么了
Why? What did he do?
妈呀
Jeez!
现在不能说
I can't talk now.
记得我的票
I want those tickets.
怎么了
What's up?
你在那边说什么
What are you talking about?
哪边
Where?
那边啊
Oh, there. Um...
没什么
Nothing.
我是说  显然  不是什么都没说
I mean, obviously, not nothing.
我们在聊天  我们就在说...
We were talking. We weren't just moving our...
我得去下厕所
I gotta go to the bathroom.
怎么回事
What the hell?
我以为你杀了他
I thought you killed him.
你真应该看看我走出门的时候
Yeah, you shoulda seen the look on your face
你脸上的表情
when I came out that door.
这可不好玩
That's not funny.
不  不好玩  简直要笑死人了
No, no, it's hysterical!
看看他们  在那里大笑
Look at 'em laughing it up.
好像这是他们的地盘似的
Just acting like they own the place.
我得去说点什么
I'm gonna say something.
别  别去  没必要
No, don't. It's not worth it.
我觉得他背叛了我们
I feel like he's cheating on us.
他没有背叛我们  莱恩  他只是...
He's not cheating on us, Ryan. He's just...
结交新朋友
branching out.
别记仇  伙计
Don't take it personally, son.
马克・吉布森
Marc Gibson.
我是黑帮组的卧底
I'm undercover on the gang task force.
我得确定能够信任你
I had to make sure I could trust ya,
如果出了岔子你会挺我
That you had my back if things got ugly.
很幸运  你通过了
Luckily, you passed.
牙买加人杀格林奇的事情你说对了
Well, you were right about the Jamaicans taking out Glitch.
住在墓地附近的人
Neighbors near the cemetery
在发生凶杀的那晚听到了枪声
heard gunshots on the night of the murder.
线人告诉我是一个叫马克西的小混混
Source tells me a low-level banger named Maxi
开的枪
was the one doing the shooting.
他躲在第一和第五大道的一个房子里
He's holed up in a building on avenue A and 5th.
出来走走  小伙子
Take a walk, fellas.
我们走吧  兄弟
Let's go, man.
马克西  为什么你要让事情这么难办呢
Maxi, why you gotta make this so hard, huh?
我们都知是你昨晚杀了那个西部帮派的小子
We both know you killed that Westie kid last night.
我想要律师
I want me lawyer.
你的律师吗
Your lawyer?
没问题  他就在这里
Sure. He's right in here.
等等
Wait!
你在干什么
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa. What are you doing?
告诉我谁杀了他  否则他们就得
Tell me you killed him or they're gonna have to
用水管把你冲出来了 马克西
hose you outta here, Maxi.
我没杀任何人
I didn't kill no one!
等等  等等
Wait! Wait!
等等  我接到个电话说有个西部帮派的人
Wait! I got a call that some Westie boy
到处说要把我们死去的朋友挖出来
was running his mouth about digging up our dead.
我去墓地伏击他
Me go out to the cemetery to ambush him,
但是我从没开过枪
but I never fire no shot!
你最好退后点
You better stand back.
这家伙会像颗葡萄那样炸开的
This guy's gonna pop like a grape.
不  等等  我发誓
No, wait! I swear!
他不是一个人  一群墨西哥人等在那里
He wasn't alone! A group of Mexicans was waiting there
靠着一辆豪华的卡迪拉克攀登
next to a tricked-out escalade!
你是说这事还涉及第三个帮派吗
Are you telling me a third gang is involved in this?
伙计  我不知道他们是谁  伙计
Man, I don't know who they are, man!
但格林奇显然是认识他们
But that Glitch clearly knew them!
他说他拿到头了  然后就突然出了乱子
He told 'em he had the heads, then things went south!
那些墨西哥人朝他开枪  然后就逃跑了
The Mexicans opened fire on him and took off running,
-我也是  -好的  好的  好的
- And so did I. - Okay, okay, okay,
那么就是墨西哥人追到了格林奇
So the Mexicans hunted down glitch,
然后杀了他
and they shot him.
或者就是他干的  还编故事骗我们
Or he did and he's making up a story.
不  不  不  我有证据
No, no, no, no, no! I can prove it!
那辆攀登上的是德克萨斯州牌照
The Escalade had Texas plates.
我看到了开头的两个字母  R和X
I saw the first two letters-- "R" And "X."
好吧  马克西
Okay, Maxi.
我们最好能查到这块牌照
But that license better check out,
不然我就回来收拾你这条小命
or I'm gonna come back here and recycle your ass.
能查到的  能查到的
It will check. It will check!
-我发誓  你们肯定能查到  -拜拜
- It'll check, man! I swear! - Bye-bye.
斯勒特  放我出去
Slaughter, get me out of here!
还有个团伙  貌似蛮可信的  是吗
Another gang. That's plausible, right?
没错
Yep.
你威胁过足够多的人
You threaten enough guys,
就能知道他们什么时候是说实话
you get a feel for their honesty.
不过刚刚你不会真打算压扁他吧
But you wouldn't have really crushed him?
当然不会啦
Nah, of course not.
更像是碾碎
It would've been more like a-a mangling.
斯勒特
Slaughter!
莱恩警探
Detective Ryan.
是我  卡塞尔
Yeah, it's Castle.
帮我查个不全的德州牌照
I have a partial Texas plate I need you to run.
开头两个字母是R和X
First letters "R" And "X."
这样啊  卡塞尔
Yeah, Castle.
这可有点难办
That's gonna be really tough for me.
我很忙的
I'm pretty busy.
是吗  你也来吗
Really? You, too, huh?
把法拉利借来
Get the Ferrari.
卡塞尔  珍妮总是缠着我
You know, Castle, Jenny's been bugging me
让我安排你跟她表亲拉莫纳见个面
to set you up with her cousin Ramona.
她是个口腔卫生医师
She's a dental hygienist.
嗯  不错
Mm-hmm. Sounds good.
-法拉利  -我这周末想借你的法拉利用用
- Ferrari. - And I want the Ferrari for the weekend.
好的  还有啊伙计  我不会忘记这事的
All right. Hey, and, buddy, I am never gonna forget this.
搞定
All right. We're all set.
好吧
All right.
明早我们就能拿到结果了
We'll get the results in the morning.
今晚嘛...我们庆祝一下
Tonight... we celebrate.
庆祝什么
Celebrate what?
庆祝你跟我一起工作的首日活了下来
Well, you survived the first day on the job with me.
你有搭档第一天就出事的吗
You ever have a partner who didn't?
我其实挺想去庆祝的  不过
You know, I'd love to, uh, celebrate, but--
不过什么
But what?
没什么  没什么
But nothing. But nothing.
我们...庆祝去
Let's... let's do this.
庆祝还能出什么事  对不
What's the worst that could happen, right?
发生什么事了
What happened?
老爸  我进了  我进了
Dad, I got in. I got in!
进什么了
Oh, where?
目前看来几乎哪都进了
Almost everywhere so far.
牛津  普林斯顿  还有萨拉劳伦斯学院
Oxford, Princeton, Sarah Lawrence.
太好了  亲爱的  我就知道你能行
That's great, honey. I-I knew it would work out.
真的吗
Really?
当然
Yeah.
那你为什么还要把这些信藏起来
Then why were you hiding the letters from me?
-什么  -拜托  老爸
- What? - Come on, dad.
邮戳上写着呢  有些信上周就到了
I can read a postmark. Some of these came last week.
我就是  对不起
Oh. I just--I'm sorry.
亲爱的  我怕你受伤而已
Honey, I-I'm just trying to protect you.
我都十八岁了
I'm 18 now.
你得相信我  我能照顾好...
You need to trust that I can take care of my...
自己
myself.
怎么了
What?
我进了斯坦福大学
I got into Stanford.
耶  太好了
Yes! Oh, great!
那不一直是你最向往的吗
That's always been your first choice, right?
可我怎么感觉你不太高兴
And yet, I sense trouble.
我不知道
I-I don't know.
我应该高兴才对
I mean, I should be happy,
可他们拒绝了我提早录取的申请
but after they shot me down for early admission...
他们当初没要你  你觉得遭到了背叛
They rejected you, and you feel betrayed.
我该怎么跨过那道坎
How am I supposed to get over that?
你气色好差
You look like crap.
给你  解酒的  能让你恢复精神
Here. Little hair of the dog. That'll get you flying right.
不用了  这也没法让时间倒流
No. It's not gonna do anything to turn back time.
我们究竟要去哪
Anyway, where are we going?
布朗克斯的修理厂
Salvage yard in the Bronx.
昨晚我自己查了那个德克萨斯州的牌照
I ran that Texas plate myself last night.
马克西说有第三方介入的事确实是真的
Turns out Maxi was telling the truth about the third player.
那辆攀登登记在一个叫凯撒・威勒斯的人名下
Escalade was registered to a Cesar Vales.
他是一个墨西哥帮派的
Runs with a Mexican gang.
据说他们想入侵纽约的地盘
Rumor has it they're making inroads into New York,
垄断这里的毒品市场
trying to corner the market on the city's crank trade.
于是威勒斯跑来这儿想跟
So Vales is coming into town trying to muscle in
西部帮派和牙买加人抢地盘
on the Westies and the Jamaicans.
是啊  这可不容易
Yeah, which ain't exactly easy to do.
如果他能让这两者互斗
Well, it would be a lot easier
那就容易得多了
if he could get them to take each other out.
不错嘛
That's good.
于是他想方设法
So he's sitting around
让西部帮派和牙买加人发生冲突
trying to think about a way to make that happen,
听到了格林奇的夸夸其谈
and he overhears Glitch running his mouth.
没错  他意识到  如果西部帮派有人被杀
Right, he realizes, if a Westie was to turn up murdered
还带着一袋子牙买加人的人头
with a bag full of Jamaican heads,
双方必然开战
both sides would go to war.
他们便能坐收渔翁之利
And they could jump in and take over their territories.
你确定我们就这样自己去找他合适吗
Are you sure it's such a good idea to go after this guy ourselves?
听马克西的口气  那帮人挺危险的
I mean, Maxi made 'em sound pretty dangerous.
小菜一碟
Piece of cake.
那家伙就是个不入流的废物而已
Guy's nothing but a two-bit punk.
他是墨西哥黑手党的高层人物
He's high-level Mexican Mafia.
非常危险
About as dangerous as they come.
缉毒局报告称  凯撒・威勒斯涉嫌
According to the D.E.A., Cesar Vales is suspected
十几起杀人案
in the deaths of over a dozen people,
其中包括三名墨西哥警察
including three cops in Mexico
被人用大锤砸死  还被碎了尸
who were killed with a sledgehammer and then cut up into pieces.
你说卡塞尔不会和斯勒特去找这个人了吧
You don't think Castle and Slaughter are going after him?
恐怕就是这样
I'd put money on it,
因为昨晚不止我一个人查了他的牌照
'cause I wasn't the only one who ran his plates last night.
斯勒特也查了
Slaughter did, too.
如果卡塞尔和斯勒特去找这家伙
If Castle and Slaughter go after this guy,
他们都会被干掉的
they're gonna both end up dead.
-我们得警告卡塞尔  -我试过了
- We need to warn Castle. - I tried,
给打他的电话都转到了语音信箱里
but his phone keeps going to voice mail.
我有种不好的预感
I got a bad feeling that
他们正在去抓威勒斯的路上
they're on their way to take down Vales right now.
你今天不会把谁碾碎吧
You're not gonna mangle anyone today, are you?
看看再说吧
I like to keep my options open.
对方人好多
There's an awful lot of 'em.
跟着我就行了
Just follow my lead.
你们好啊
Hola.
先生们  我代表纽约警局
Gentlemen, on behalf of the NYPD,
欢迎各位来到上帝之域最棒的城市
I'd like to welcome you to the greatest city on god's green earth.
除非你想让你的朋友
Unless you want your friends to see
看到你脑子里什么样
what the inside of your head looks like,
让开
back off.
有什么问题  警官
Wow. Now what seems to be the problem, officer?
你是威勒斯
You Vales?
就是我
That's me.
你知道麦克・莱利这个人吗
Name Michael Reilly mean anything to you?
也叫格林奇
A.K.A. Glitch.
没什么意义
No. I'm afraid not.
那可有意思了  因为有人看到
That's funny, 'cause I got an eyewitness
你和你的娘们
that puts you and your girls here
两晚前在皇后区向他开枪
shooting the hell outta him in Queens two nights ago.
那可真有趣
That is funny.
喂  你  你的警章呢
Hey, you. Where's your badge?
在他别的衣服里
In his other coat.
威勒斯  我们已经了解你的计划了
Yeah, Vales, we know all about your plan.
利用格林奇来引发帮派斗争
Use Glitch to spark a gang war
这样你就能把自己的毒品生意搬到纽约了
so you could move your drug business into New York.
喔  你的搭档
Wow. Your partner here,
他挺亢奋啊
he's pretty high-strung, isn't he?
是啊
Yeah.
-亢奋  是吧  -喔
- High-strung, huh? - Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
纽约警局
Hey! NYPD!
纽约警局  把手举起来
NYPD! Let me see your hands!
派对结束了
The party's over.
太遗憾了  才刚刚开始有点意思
That's too bad, because this was just getting interesting.
我要是你  就把事情都安排妥当
If I were you, I'd get your affairs in order,
因为我还会回来的
'cause I'll be back.
斯勒特
Hey! Slaughter.
像那样没有后援就冲进去
Going in there like that without backup,
把平民百姓陷于危险之中
putting a civilian in harm's way,
那不只鲁莽  还是警察失职
that's not only reckless, that is bad police work.
你该庆幸我们追踪到卡塞尔的手机
You're just lucky that we traced Castle's phone
及时找到了你们
and we found you guys in time.
你以为我会感谢你们几乎毁了我的计划吗
What, you think I'm gonna thank you for almost ruining my play?
你还有计划
You had a play?
我总有计划  得让事情升级
I always have a play. Had to escalate things.
这样我就能找出他们当中的弱者了
That way I could find the weak member of the herd.
那个孩子
That kid.
没错
Exactly.
我们就要靠他扳倒威勒斯
He's the one I'm gonna get to flip on Vales
只需想办法把他单独找出来
once I figure out how to separate him from the pack.
我们一起工作这么些年
Who knew all these years we've been working together
还不知你有意求死
that you had a death wish?
那个吗  那没什么不好
Come on, that? That wasn't bad.
斯勒特有个计划
Slaughter had a plan.
是啊  他的计划就是害死你
Yeah, he had a plan to get you killed.
现在下楼
是斯勒特
It's slaughter.
我得走了
I gotta go.
好吧
All right.
下次我们可能就不会去救你了
Next time, we might not be there to save you.
你得做点什么
You need to do something.
埃斯波  如果一个人拼命想离开巢穴
Espo, if the guy is hell-bent on leaving the nest,
那我没什么可做的了
then there is nothing that I can do about it.
你不是真这么想吧
You don't really feel that way, do you?
别听那些人唧唧歪歪  夏洛克
Don't you listen to those whiners, Sherlock.
你有种的
You got balls.
是  或许我刚刚没必要
Yeah, I may have needlessly put you
让你在威勒斯那儿犯险
in a little harm's way there with Vales,
但是还是有成效的
but seeing as it paid off...
有成效是什么意思
What do you mean, paid off?
-那是什么  -你说什么呢
- What was that? - What was what?
伙计  这么做不好吧
Hey, come on, man! It's not cool!
后备箱里有人吗
Is there someone in the trunk?
吉尔伯托・门多萨  我们要找的软肋
Gilberto Mendoza, our weak link.
快点放我出去  伙计
Get me the hell outta here, man!
告诉我我们只是和他谈谈
Please tell me that we are just going to talk to him.
差不多吧
Yeah, pretty much.
伙计  怎么回事  你不能这么做
Come on, man! What's going on?! You can't do that!
这么做不对  快停下
This is wrong. You gotta stop.
除非他告发威勒斯
Not till he flips on Vales.
你听见了吗  吉尔伯托
You hear that, Gilberto?
你想从后备箱出来  唯一的方法
Only way you're gettin' out of that trunk
就是供出你的老板
is if you rat out your boss.
告诉你吧  我是什么都不会说的
Well, guess what. I'm not sayin' nothing!
还记得你说我欠我人情的事吗
Hey, remember that favor you promised me?
有个民众审查委员会找我麻烦
There's this civilian review board thing coming up.
过度用武投诉  全都是废话  对吧
Excessive force complaints. Total B.S., right?
总之  你不是跟市长是朋友什么的
Anyway, you being a friend of the mayor and all,
我想你去说句话
I figure a statement from you
一定会让那些指控都撤销的  是吧
would go a long way to making those charges go away, right?
你疯了
You're crazy.
是"不"的意思吗
Is that a no?
我做  你停下我就做
I'll do it! I'll do it if you stop!
非常好  下周二
Outstanding. Next Tuesday.
上午九点准时
9:00 a.m. Sharp.
我会给你发邮件的
I'll send you an e-mail.
伙计  我知道我的权利
Hey, man, I know my rights, all right?
这是绑架  滥用执法权
This is kidnapping. Police abuse.
我也知道一些事  吉尔伯托
I know something, too, Gilberto.
你在德克萨斯州少管所里有个弟弟
You got a brother in juvie back in Texas.
可怜的海克特
Poor little Hector.
我听说他每天晚上都以泪洗面
I hear he cries himself to sleep every night.
你到底在做什么
Hey, what the hell are you doing?
就是和吉尔伯托聊会儿天
Just having a little chat here with Gilberto.
听着  除非你想让海克特有什么不测
Listen, unless you want something very bad to happen to Hector,
你得帮我扳倒威勒斯  行吧
you're gonna help me bury Vales, aren't ya?
听见了吗
Aren't ya?
-好  -好什么
- Okay. - Okay, what?
我需要听你说咒语
I need to hear the magic words.
威勒斯杀了格林奇
Vales killed Glitch.
胜利
Yes. Victory.
威勒斯当时在想办法抢过牙买加人
Vales was looking for a way to take over the Jamaicans'
和西部帮派的地盘
and the Westies' turf.
刚好我们听说有个西部帮派废物
That's when we heard about this punk-ass westie
想要证明自己  威勒斯看到了机会
trying to prove himself, and Vales saw his chance.
他说服格林奇
He convinced Glitch that
如果他挖出几个牙买加人并砍掉他们头
if he dug up a couple of Jamaicans and cut off their heads,
就能让他回到他西部帮派的伙伴当中
that it would get him back in tight with his westie pals.
威勒斯想用几个人头来引发一场帮派斗争
So Vales wanted to use the heads to spark a gang war?
让西部帮派和牙买加人都投入其中
For the Westies and Jamaicans to go at it
直到人都死光了
till no one's left standing,
他可以轻松过来占领地盘
then he waltzes in, takes over the territory?
是的
Yeah.
在墓地发生了什么
What went down at the cemetery?
威勒斯让格林奇去挖尸体
Vales got Glitch to dig up the bodies.
计划是杀了他
The plan was to kill him
伪装成牙买加人干的样子
and make it look like the Jamaicans did it.
格林奇一定是察觉到了什么
And Glitch must have sensed it or something,
我们一开火他就跑掉了
'cause he took off right as we started opening fire.
讲讲谋杀的事
Tell me about the murder.
孩子  我知道你有点害怕
Look, kid, I know you're scared,
我也有点粗暴
and I was a little rough.
但是我与检察官和联调局的人谈过了
But I talked to the D.A. and the feds.
他们说只要你配合我的调查
They said, you cooperate with me,
你弟弟将减到有期徒刑
your brother's sentence will be reduced to time served,
你们兄弟俩都将作为联邦证人受到保护
and both of you get a free ride into witsec.
赶紧告诉我怎么回事
So tell me how it went down.
我们追他  堵住了他
We chased him, we cornered him.
在天桥下面吗
Under the overpass?
是的
Yeah.
然后呢
And?
然后威勒斯两枪将他毙命
And then Vales shot him twice and just left him for dead.
到底多少枪
How many--how many times?
三枪
Three.
他开了三枪
He shot him three times.
你认为你在干什么
What do you think you're doing?
结案啊
Closing this case.
我拿到了威勒斯的逮捕令
I got an arrest warrant for Vales
就放在我口袋里等着派上用场呢
burning a hole in my pocket.
你在受审时指示那孩子按你的意图说
You coached that kid through his interrogation.
哪有
What? Nah, nah.
我只是帮助他回忆而已
I just refreshed his recollection.
真的吗  因为根据他的语气
Really? 'cause the way he was talking,
他甚至没有目击这起谋杀
he didn't even witness that murder.
嘿
Hey. H--
威勒斯身上的命案多到你不敢想象
Vales has bodies on him like you wouldn't believe--
女人  小孩  警察都有
Women, children, cops.
有机会逮住他  我绝不会浪费
And I got a chance to put him away. I'm gonna take it.
问题在于  你加入还是退出
The question is, are you in or out?
我想我还是退出吧
I guess I'm out.
真可惜
Well, that's a shame.
我对你寄予厚望呢  夏洛克
I had high hopes for you, Sherlock.
没想到你如此胆小怕事
Never thought you'd punk out on me like this.
嘿
Hey.
我需要帮助
I need some help.
抱歉  卡塞尔  有案子在身
Sorry, Castle. Caught a murder.
跟贝克特说去
Talk to Beckett.
嘿
Hey.
你最近怎样
How's it going?
别拐弯抹角  卡塞尔  你想要什么
You can skip the small talk, Castle. What do you want?
斯勒特做得过头了
Slaughter went too far.
那是他的作风啊
Well, isn't that what he does,
绝赞威武  风光无两
Along with kicking ass and taking names?
他为了能抓捕威勒斯
He pressured a kid into making a false statement
威逼证人做假口供
so he could arrest Vales.
于是你找我去弥补
So you came to me so I can fix it?
你完全有理由生气
You have every right to be mad.
你向我警告过斯勒特的为人  我却当耳旁风
You warned me about Slaughter, and I wouldn't listen.
我只是想弥补这一切
I'm just trying to make this right.
这不是我的案子  卡塞尔
It's not my case, Castle.
即使我想帮忙
Even if I wanted to help,
我们也有一套严格的规定
we've got strict rules about
限制我们干涉其他警察的案子
interfering in another cop's investigation.
我不是要你帮我的忙
I'm not asking you to do it for me.
我是求你为了
I'm asking you to do it
不使真凶逃脱惩罚而这样做
so the real killer doesn't get away with murder.
你这么明目张胆的操纵我
What makes you think I'm actually gonna fall
我凭什么上钩
for that blatant manipulation?
因为我说的是实话
Because it's true.
这是什么
What's this?
监控录像拍摄显示威勒斯的车子
A traffic cam shot of Vales' car
离公墓有十个街区  朝格林奇被杀所处天桥
10 blocks from the cemetery, heading away from the overpass
反方向行驶
where Glitch was killed.
11点57
11:57.
格林奇是午夜之后被害的
Glitch was killed after midnight.
这表明威勒斯不可能杀害他
This shows that Vales couldn't have killed him.
你这是为我做的吗
You did this for me?
你一直都在保护我
All this time, you had my back.
我让莱恩查了监控录像
I had Ryan run a traffic cam search
那时他正在帮某人调车牌
while he was pulling a plate.
这不是确凿证据  卡塞尔
It's not a smoking gun, Castle.
知道吗  你连威勒斯的脸都看不到
Okay? You can't even see Vales' face in that photo.
这还不足以使斯勒特改变想法
It's not enough to change Slaughter's mind
除非你还有别的证据
unless you've got something else.
还有一个说不通的疑点
There is one more thing that doesn't make sense.
这是那块区域的地图
This is a map of the area.
这里是公墓  这里是天桥
Here's the cemetery. Here's the overpass.
但是若要到达那里  格林奇得翻1.8米的围墙
But to get to it, Glitch would have to climb a 6-foot fence.
一街区之隔就有个地铁  他为何还要那样做呢
Why do that when there's a subway station a block away?
如果可以逃跑为啥还要躲藏呢
Why hide when you can run?
也许我们能解开谜底
Maybe we can find out.
根据鉴证组报告
According to the C.S.U. report,
格林奇是在这附近被射中的
Glitch was shot somewhere around here. Uh-huh.
他蹒跚着逃走
He staggered away
最终死在柱子的另一边
and ended up on the other side of that pillar.
那么你认为威勒斯的计划就是利用格林奇
So you think that Vales' plan was to use Glitch
和牙买加黑帮的头目来挑起黑帮火并
and the jamaican heads to start up a gang war?
是的  有什么不对吗
Yeah. Why?
我不知道  卡塞尔  跟我了解到的证据对不上
I don't know, Castle. That's not what I'm seeing.
假设我是威勒斯
Let's say I'm Vales
射杀了格林奇挑起火并
and I shoot Glitch to start that war.
你认为哪儿会是
Where do you think would be
最佳抛尸地点
the best spot to drop off that body?
西部帮派的地盘
In the middle of westie territory.
没错  那为何他会将尸体留在这儿
Exactly. So why did he leave it here?
糟糕
Oh, crap.
好吧
Well...
想象一下当我带着凶手到分局  听说你们
Imagine my surprise when I got to the station with my killer,
在我的犯罪现场搅和的时候有多惊讶吧
and I hear you're stirring up my crime scene.
听着  我可以解释
Okay, look, I can explain.
省省吧  他不懂规矩  但你是知道的
Save it. He doesn't know any better, but you do.
我知道的是你对一个18岁的少年
What I know is that you coerced a confession
刑讯逼供
out of an 18-year-old kid.
我没有逼供杰克
I didn't coerce Jack.
他老大手里杀死的人的尸体
He works for a guy who's got a trail of bodies
多得连起来都能排到格兰德河了
that stretches all the way back to the rio grande.
如果这次不抓住他
If he doesn't go down for this,
他还会残害更多人
the body count just grows.
我们有监控录像显示威勒斯的凯迪拉克
We got a traffic video camera photo of Vales' escalade
在案发时离现场有10街区呢
10 blocks from here when the murder went down.
那有怎样  你能看见他在车里吗
Yeah, so what? Could you see him in the car?
看不清
Not exactly.
如果他的律师得到了这个证据
And if his lawyer gets ahold of it,
他们就可以提出合理质疑
you've handed him reasonable doubt,
威勒斯就会免于刑罚
And Vales walks.
也许他本就不该受罚
Maybe he deserves to walk.
他应该被五马分尸
He deserves to be pulled apart by horses.
但是法律不允许我这样做
But the law says I can't do that.
但是我能做的是
But what I can do is,
让他下辈子都在牢里度过
I can lock him up in prison for the rest of his life.
现在问题在于  你们要么别插手
Now the question is, are you gonna back off
要么我就举报你们干涉我的案子
or am I gonna have to report you for jumping my case?
你做你该做的  斯勒特
You do what you gotta do, Slaughter.
我做我该做的
And I'll do the same.
多谢
Thanks.
在我被警监狠狠教训之前
We got about an hour to figure out who really killed Glitch
我们还有一个小时查清
before I get called to the carpet
杀死格林奇的真凶
by the chief of detectives.
他会怎么对你
What can he do to you?
最好的情况是
Well, best-case scenario,
停职
he suspends me.
最坏的情况呢
And worst-case scenario?
糟了
Crap.
我扮演格林奇
So I'm Glitch.
我挖出三具尸体  砍下了他们的头
I just dug up three bodies, cut the heads off 'em,
很恐怖
which was horrible,
试图以此跟西部帮派示好
to try and win my way back in with the westies.
然后那个我以为是在帮我的
And then the kindly Mexican gentlemen
"善良"的墨西哥绅士
I thought were helping me
突然拔出枪想要杀死我
suddenly pull out guns and try to kill me.
拼命逃跑
Running for my life,
一直跑到围栏这边
I end up on the wrong side of this fence.
这里你能看到地铁的标志
Where you can see a sign for the subway.
明明可以向右跳上列车离开
So why would you climb a barbed wire fence
为什么还要爬过这个带倒刺铁丝的围栏呢
when can just hang a right and hop a train outta here?
恐惧
Fear.
我只知道  墨西哥人
For all I know, the Mexicans
沿着街道开车找我
are driving the streets looking for me.
这些街道上灯火通明  我很容易暴露
With all these street lights on, I'd be a sitting duck.
而在这下面  一片漆黑
But under here, it would be pitch black,
所以我爬过围栏躲起来
so I climb the fence and I hide.
能逃脱为什么还要躲起来呢
Why hide when you can escape?
因为我不仅仅是躲着
Because I wasn't just hiding.
我在等待  因为叫了后援
I was waiting. I called for help.
但他们发现格林奇的尸体时
But when they found Glitch's body,
并没有在他身上找到手机  所以
he didn't have a phone on him, so--
所以要么是凶手拿走了  要么...
So either the killer took it or...
要么就是他使用了付费电话
Or he used that pay phone.
为什么叫我来这里
Why'd you call me down here?
因为我们有充足的证据证明不是威勒斯杀了格林奇
Because we have definitive proof that Vales didn't kill Glitch.
你想当面让我难堪吗
And you want to rub my face in it?
不是
No.
斯勒特  听好  我们是不同的警察
Look, Slaughter, we're different kinds of cops.
没错
Yeah.
尽管我不赞同你的方法
And although I'm not a fan of your methods,
我知道  明知真凶还逍遥法外
I know you don't want to send an innocent man to jail
你是不会让其他人无辜入狱的
when you know that the real killer is still out there.
好吧  那么是谁杀了格林奇
Okay. So who killed Glitch?
我们知道他打给你了  布莱恩
We know he called you, Brian.
你儿子在被杀前半小时
Your son dialed your cell from that pay phone
用那个付费电话打了你的手机
about a half an hour before he was murdered,
而且你接了电话
and you answered that call.
我们还有凶案前后
We also have surveillance photos
你在地铁站的
of you at that subway stop from before
监控照片
and after the murder.
这么些年
All those years...
这么些烂摊子
All those screwups--
对于像你这样有胆识的人来说一定很难忍受吧
Must have been unbearable for a stand-up guy like you,
布莱恩  是吗
Huh, Brian?
格林奇打给你  告诉你他又一次
And then Glitch calls you to tell you that he screwed up
搞糟了
again.
但是这一次  很特别  对吗
But this time, it was different, wasn't it?
他逾矩了
He'd crossed the line.
他是你的儿子
He was your son.
所以我要对他负责
Which made him my responsibility.
所以我做了该做的
So I did what had to be done.
他一点都不吃惊
He wasn't even surprised.
就好像他等这一刻等了一辈子
'twas if he'd been waiting for it his whole life.
那你为什么不带走他们的头
Then why didn't you take the heads?
那样的话  这一切都不会追查到你和西部帮派
That way, none of this would come back on you and the westies.
我开枪之后他就消失在了黑暗里
He vanished into the dark after I'd shot him.
即使只有最后一口气
Even with his last breath,
那孩子也要毁了我
that boy managed to screw me up.
至少最终你给布莱恩定了罪
Well, at least you'll finally get a conviction on Brian.
这也多少算是有点安慰了
That's gotta be some consolation.
但是威勒斯还没被抓到
But Vales still walks.
抱歉
Excuse me.
律师
Counselor.
我能和你的委托人说两句吗
Can I speak with your client for a second?
她可能想要我的签名
She probably wants my autograph.
你自我感觉良好  我知道
You feel cocky. I get it.
你刚刚摆脱谋杀控诉
You just dodged a murder rap.
今晚大概要出去和你的弟兄们庆祝一下
Probably gonna go out tonight and celebrate with your boys,
你也应该狂欢痛饮一番
and you should paint the town.
但是明天早晨
But then in the morning,
我要你滚出这个城市
I want you to get the hell out of my city.
但是我喜欢这里
But I like it here.
你可能现在喜欢
You might like it right now.
但是明天开始  你就会见识到
But starting tomorrow, you're gonna see
纽约警局全部警力
just how hard a city New York can be
都要弄垮你的日子
when the full force of the NYPD
是多么艰辛
comes crashing down on you.
三万警察
With 30,000 cops
把这列入日常工作表中  会让你的生活
making it their daily duty to make your life
生不如死
a living hell.
律师  你现在可以带他走了
Counselor, you can take him away now.
真性感
Oh, that is sexy.
干嘛  你又想因为这句话揍我吗
What, you want to hit me for that, too?
不想
No.
这拳是为了你不帮我
That's for not having my back.
还有  如果我看到
Oh, and if I ever see
你小说中有类似我的角色
a character in one of your novels like me,
那我们就要好好谈谈了
we're gonna have words.
那么  我们周二听证会见吧
So I'm gonna see you at the hearing on Tuesday, Right?
好的
You got it.
好极了
Outstanding.
探长  如果你想要痛快喝酒
Detective, you ever want to go on a date
酒醉打架  之后火辣亲热
that ends in hot sex after a drunken fistfight,
你知道在哪能找到我
you know where to find me.
是...啊  做你的梦吧
Uh, yeah, in never-gonna-happen land.
非常感谢你的帮助
Thanks very much for your help.
不客气  卡塞尔
No problem, Castle.
这是搭档应该做的事
It's what partners are supposed to do.
享受成功的荣耀吗
Basking in the glory of you?
不是  是想弄明白应该怎么做
No, trying to figure out what to do.
斯坦福一直是我梦寐以求的学校
Stanford has always been my dream school.
但是如果他们首次拒绝信
But what if their initial rejection
是在暗示我
was the university sending me a sign
我最好申请其他学校呢
that I'm better off somewhere else?
你觉得你去其他学校更好吗
You think you'd be better off somewhere else?
我不知道
I don't know.
你觉得呢
Do you?
我也不知道
I don't know, either.
我想问题是
I guess the question is,
你是不是渴望到
do you want it badly enough...
可以不顾之前的伤害
to get over being hurt?
你知道什么能帮上忙吗
You know what I think would help with this decision?
-冰淇淋  -冰淇淋
- Ice cream. - Ice cream.
比你快
Race you.
你赖皮
That's cheating!